<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.8">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>We define numerical methods that are based on discretizations preserving the properties of their continuous counterparts to be <bold>mimetic</bold>.</para><para>The <bold>Mimetic Methods Toolkit (MTK)</bold> is a C++11 library for mimetic numerical methods. It is a set of classes for <bold>mimetic interpolation</bold>, <bold>mimetic quadratures</bold>, and <bold>mimetic finite difference</bold> methods for the <bold>numerical solution of ordinary and partial differential equations</bold>.</para><sect1 id="index_1section_mtk_concerns">
<title>MTK Concerns</title>
<para>Since collaborative development efforts are very important, we have divided the library&apos;s source code according to the purpose the classes possess. These divisions (or <bold>concerns</bold>) are grouped by layers, and are hierarchically related by the dependencies they have among them. One concern is said to depend on another one, if the classes the first concern includes, rely on the classes the second concern includes. In order of dependence these are:<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Foundations.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Enumerations.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Execution Tools.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Data Structures.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Numerical Methods.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Grids.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Mimetic Operators.</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1section_wrappers">
<title>MTK Wrappers</title>
<para>The MTK collection of wrappers is:</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>MMTK: MATLAB wrappers collection for MTK; intended for sequential computations.</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para><para>Others are being considered.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1section_authors">
<title>Contact, Support and Credits</title>
<para>The GitHub repository is: <ulink url="https://github.com/ejspeiro/MTK">https://github.com/ejspeiro/MTK</ulink></para><para>The MTK is developed by researchers and adjuncts to the <ulink url="http://www.csrc.sdsu.edu/">Computational Science Research Center (CSRC)</ulink> at <ulink url="http://www.sdsu.edu/">San Diego State University (SDSU)</ulink>.</para><para>Currently the developers are:</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Eduardo J. Sanchez, PhD - esanchez at mail dot sdsu dot edu</bold> - ejspeiro</para></listitem><listitem><para>Jose E. Castillo, PhD - jcastillo at mail dot sdsu dot edu</para></listitem><listitem><para>Guillermo F. Miranda, PhD - unigrav at hotmail dot com</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><sect2 id="index_1subsection_acknowledgements">
<title>Acknowledgements and Contributions</title>
<para>The authors would like to acknowledge valuable advising, contributions and feedback, from research personnel at the Computational Science Research Center at San Diego State University, which were vital to the fruition of this work. Specifically, our thanks go to (alphabetical order):</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Mohammad Abouali, Ph.D.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Dany De Cecchis, Ph.D.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Otilio Rojas, Ph.D.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Julia Rossi, Ph.D.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Christopher P. Paolini, PhD - paolini at engineering dot sdsu dot edu</para></listitem><listitem><para>Johnny Corbino.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Raul Vargas-Navarro. </para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para></sect2>
</sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
